Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're doing
something that makes a lot of people
very nervous when they come to America.
That's right today we are
arriving to the airport but before
we can leave we need to pass
through customs and immigration.
All right customs and immigration so anyone
who comes into the United States, American,
not American, doesn't matter you have to
go through this gate so let's learn about
some of these phrases and
questions in today's dialogue.
Good afternoon, passport
and arrival card please.
Here you are.
Where are you coming from?
China.
Is this your country of birth or residence?
I just work there.
What is the purpose of your
visit to the United States?
I'm here on vacation.
How long do you plan to
stay in the United States?
Almost three weeks.
Sir you didn't fill out
the information on
your arrival card of
where you'll be staying.
Oh I'm sorry but there are a
couple different places that we'll
travel to within the United
States so I wasn't sure what to put.
You must specify an address on the place
where you will spend most of your time.
Okay.
Here you are.
Do you have enough means to
support yourself while you're here?
Yes I have some travelers
checks and two credit cards.
Very good.
Do you have anything to declare?
Nope.
I only have my clothes and camera.
Very well sir.
Welcome to the United States.
Enjoy your visit.
All right we're back so now let's take a
look at some of that language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first thing we have to
learn about is the arrival card.
So good afternoon, passport
and arrival card please.
That's the first line of the dialogue.
That's right.
The arrival card usually
you will get on the
airplane before you land and basically you
just have to put your name, your passport
number, where you're
from and basic information
like this that you must give
to the immigration officer.
Great.
So what is the opposite of arrival card?
What do you fill out
when you leave America?
That's right.
Some countries require you
to fill out a departure card.
All right.
So some countries
not all but you'll usually
get an arrival card
which means that you
have to give your name
and basic information.
That's right.
So we are at the, we're
talking to the immigration
officer and he asks, is this your
country of birth or residence?
All right.
Let's break that down.
Country of birth.
So birth, birthday that, that
makes me think of where I was born.
So what country were you born in?
That's another way to ask this question.
That's right.
So since we said we are
coming from China, the
immigration officer
wants to know if we are
Chinese or if we simply live there
and that's why he says or residence.
So residence, it's a noun, it's a thing.
My country of residence
is the place where I live.
So I'm American but
maybe my country of
residence is France
because I live in France.
That's right.
So it's, it's different
from your country of birth.
Now moving on when
the immigration officer was
asking us about money,
we said that we have
some travelers checks
and two credit cards.
All right.
So credit cards are pretty clear.
But what exactly are travelers checks and
how are they different from normal checks?
So travelers checks
are kind of a convenient
way to carry money
because you have these
little pieces of paper that
have a certain amount on them.
So for example, $500 each.
If you lose it, it's not
a problem because no
one can exchange those
checks for cash unless it's you.
All right.
So my travelers check.
I buy these from the bank.
They have my name on them,
my passport number on them.
And to spend them as
money, I need to show my
passport or proof of
identification or proof of identity.
So basically, if someone
steals my travelers
checks, if I lose my
travelers checks, I don't
have to worry because no
one else can spend them.
But me.
Exactly.
They were very, very popular back
before credit cards were so popular now.
You don't really see too many travelers
checks, but it's still convenient.
All right.
So a lot of language
there when we listen to
our dialogue again, good afternoon
passport and arrival card, please.
Here you are.
Where are you coming from?
China.
Your country of birth or residence?
I just work there.
What is the purpose of your
visit to the United States?
I'm here on vacation.
How long do you plan to
stay in the United States?
Almost three weeks.
Sir, you didn't fill out
the information on
your arrival card of
where you'll be staying.
Oh, I'm sorry, but
there are a couple of
different places that
we'll travel to within
the United States, so I
wasn't sure what to put.
You must specify an address on the place
where you will spend most of your time.
Okay.
Here you are.
Do you have enough means to
support yourself while you're here?
Yes.
I have some travelers
checks and two credit cards.
Very good.
Do you have anything to declare?
Nope.
I only have my clothes and camera.
Very well, sir.
Welcome to the United States.
Enjoy your visit.
All right, we're back,
so now let's take a
look at some of those
key questions that the
immigration officer asks
us on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
At this first sentence,
this first question
is actually something that a lot of
learners of English have a hard time with.
Where are you coming from?
Right.
So the immigration
officer is sitting there at
his desk and you are
arriving on an airplane.
So what he wants to know is
what country are you arriving from?
So if I am on a
flight from France to
America, I say I'm arriving
from France, I'm running.
I'm coming from France.
That's right.
But here's a big thing.
What if he says where are you from?
Now he's asking you for your nationality.
So then you wouldn't say
France because you're not French.
I'm not French.
I'm American.
So I'd say I am American,
but I'm coming from France.
Yes.
Very typical question that
English learners confuse
because, as you can
see, it's very, very similar.
But you just have one word that you add
on and it completely changes the question.
So when the immigration officer
asks you, where are you coming from?
You tell them what country
you got on the plane.
All right.
So where did you leave to come to America?
Did you leave from France, China, Ghana?
So that's the answer to that question.
Exactly.
I'm immigration
officers will never ask you
where you are from because
they will see your passport.
They know.
Yeah.
So, okay.
Now, once we give them
our passport, we tell them
that we just work in
China, we're not Chinese.
He asks, what is the purpose
of your visit to the United States?
What's the purpose of your visit?
Now purpose means goal or aim.
So there are a couple
of standard answers to
this question, but basically the
immigration officer wants to know.
Why are you in America?
Why are you coming here?
That's right.
So you have, as Catherine says, a
couple of different ways of answering that.
We're saying here that
we are here on vacation.
I'm here on vacation.
Tourism.
Right.
Seeing family, these are
all acceptable answers.
That's right.
So now that we've
told the officer all of
this information, we actually forgot to
fill out our address on our arrival card.
So he says that we must specify an address.
All right.
So to specify, this is a verb, it means
to indicate or write down or identify.
Because right now, there is no address.
We're going to stay.
So to specify means to basically to
tell someone where it is, to be exact.
That's right.
So you need to specify an
address of where you will
be during the time
you're in the United States.
It could be a hotel any place.
Right.
But it can't be like Chicago.
No, it can't be a city.
It's got to be an address.
So 10 South Street Chicago, Illinois.
That's right.
Now we told the immigration
officer where we're going to be.
And he asks a very important
question, also very, very common.
Do you have enough means to
support yourself while you are here?
So means in this instance
means resources or money.
So do you have enough money
to pay for your housing, your food?
That's the question.
So means to support yourself.
That means, can you pay for yourself?
Who's paying for this trip?
Exactly.
So this is why we say,
yeah, we have some
travelers checks and a
couple of credit cards.
And lastly, we also need to answer
if we have anything to declare.
But what does this mean to declare what?
To declare at customs, okay, but we
don't normally ask to declare at customs.
We just say, do you
have anything to declare?
This is because normally,
when we travel to
other countries, there are
special taxes for certain goods.
For example, if I want to come to America
and I have three bottles of wine, I have to
give one away because I'm only
allowed to bring in two bottles.
Right.
So I have to declare two
bottles of wine or money.
I'm only allowed to bring $10,000.
If I bring $15,000, I
have to write that down
and say, I have this extra
money and then I pay tax.
Right.
So basically, they will ask you,
what are you bringing to America?
And if there are special
things like money or
things you will sell or alcohol,
cigarettes, you have to declare these.
You have to explain what you're carrying.
That's right.
So this is a very important question also.
Most of the time, obviously, if you're on
tourism, you don't have much to declare.
But maybe like if
Catherine says, maybe you
are going to buy a
house in the United States
and you have $20,000 in your
luggage, then you need to tell them that.
That's right.
So that's called declaring
to declare at customs.
All right.
So let's take a break and listen
to our dialogue one last time.
Good afternoon.
Passport and arrival card, please.
Here you are.
Where are you coming from?
China.
Is this your country of birth or residence?
I just work there.
What is the purpose of your
visit to the United States?
I'm here on vacation.
How long do you plan to
stay in the United States?
Almost three weeks.
Sir, you didn't fill out
the information on
your arrival card of
where you'll be staying.
Oh, I'm sorry.
But there are a couple
of different places
that we'll travel to within the United
States, so I wasn't sure what to put.
You must specify an address on the place
where you will spend most of your time.
Okay.
Here you are.
Do you have enough means to
support yourself while you're here?
Yes, I have some travelers'
checks and two credit cards.
Very good.
Do you have anything to declare?
Nope.
I only have my clothes and camera.
Very well, sir.
Welcome to the United States.
Enjoy your visit.
All right.
So when you're arriving
to immigration, obviously
all these questions
are very, very common.
You will be asked.
But when you're
arriving there, there are
actually two different
sections that you have to go to.
Right?
That's right.
There's two different lines.
Maybe many lines, but
they'll have a sign on top.
One says US passports
or US passport holders.
And that means the line for
Americans coming home to America.
But for most people
who are traveling to
America, they're foreigners,
they have to go to the other line.
So that's non-US passport holders.
That's right.
Now, remember that you
don't really have to get
nervous when you're
talking to the immigration
officer, you know, just have to take it
easy and just try to answer the questions.
Most of them will speak
a couple of words in
many popular languages
like Chinese or Spanish
or Arabic, because
obviously some people that
go on holiday to the United States,
maybe they don't speak English.
That's right.
So there's nothing to be worried about.
These people are there to
make sure that America is safe.
They want to check the bags.
They want to know
who's coming into the
country, and they're just doing their
job being basically policing the borders.
But it's pretty simple.
The most annoying part of
customs, for me, is waiting in line.
Yeah, you have so
many people arrive at the
same time that you can wait in
line maybe an hour or sometimes.
Sometimes.
So again, just be
honest, and I think people
will try to understand you
if you're having a hard time.
Exactly.
So if you have any
questions or comments,
you can find us at EnglishPod.com,
and we'll see you guys there.
Bye.